in this tutorial i'm going to show you
how to do a triangle granny
so this will be good if you're using it
in a blanket for example or if you want
to keep making the triangle bigger so
that you can make a shawl so it's really
adaptable
i am using this karen simply soft in the
color fuchsia and a four and a half
millimeter hook to go with it but you
can of course use whichever yarn and
hook you prefer
you will also need a pair of scissors
and a darning needle for sewing in your
ends as always i'll leave all of the
information in the description box below
so click that show more button and
you'll see a link which will take you to
my website you'll have all of the
information there including the written
pattern so that you can save it to your
pinterest board for later as always if
you like my tutorials don't forget to
give them a thumbs up leave me a comment
share with your friends
and don't forget to subscribe and click
that bell button to keep up to date with
all of my latest videos
okay let's get started
okay so first of all we're going to
start off with a slip knot and you can
do this in whichever method you prefer
you want to go ahead and insert your
crochet hook and we're going to start
off by chaining four
such yarn over one
two three
and four
we're going to join with a slip stitch
into that very first chain
so yarn over and then just pull the yarn
through
both of those loops so that we're making
a center circle and this is where we're
going to start off
so for row one we're going to
chain four
one
two
three
and four this chain four counts as a
treble
and a chain one um here and throughout
the work
so now we're going to continue to work
in this circle
and we're going to do three treble
crochets
so remember i'm working in uk terms when
i say treble
that is a uk term in the us that is
known as a double crochet so
if you're in the us this is double
crochet plus a chain one uk terms treble
crochet plus a chain one
so we're now going to do those three
treble crochets or double crochets if
you're in the us which is yarn over
insert into that very center of that
circle
yarn over and pull through
you'll have three loops on your hook
yarn over
pull through two loops you'll have two
loops on your hook
yarn over pull through two i'll just go
through that again yarn over
insert
yarn over pull through
three loops on the hook
two loops
and yarn over pull through two loops if
you need slowed down versions of these
stitches please feel free to check out
my absolute beginner's series and then
come back to this video
so we've just done those two trebles we
need to do one more
we're going to chain two one
and two that's going to create a corner
and then we're going to do three trebles
into that very same center circle one
two
and three
that chain two that we've just done
actually creates the peak of the
triangle
so what we want to do now is almost make
a mirror image
of what we've done here
so we're going to
chain one
and then do one more treble into that
center circle
so as i say this is the flat side of the
triangle that we're building
and then this is the peak
so for row two
we're going to chain four
one
two
three and four
and turn our work as i said before that
counts as a stitch plus a chain one
we're going to do three trebles into
this chain one space
one
two
and three
we're going to chain one
and then we're going to work into this
chain two space just here so we're going
to do a little cluster of stitches into
this chain two which is where the peak
is so we want to continue to build this
peak
we're going to do three trebles
one
two
and three
chain two one and two that's building
our peak of our triangle
and then three trebles one
two
and three
we're going to chain one to move
ourselves over to this chain one space
here
and we're going to do
three trebles
one
two
three
chain one
and a treble
so we're
creating a mirror image
of what we did on the opposite side
now we're going to move on to row three
now you can either stop at row three if
that's the desired size that you want
for example if you're using it
at the edge of a blanket
or you can repeat row three over and
over again until you get to the size
that you want so if you're making a
shawl a triangular shawl you can just
keep repeating this row
so we're going to chain
four one
two
three and four
turn our work
and then we're going to do three trebles
into this chain one space
so always three trebles into this first
chain one space
that's two
and
three and then we're going to chain one
to move across to the next space
now the more rows you build the more
spaces you will have until you get to
the peak of your triangle so this will
just be the same
until you get to this peak of the
triangle
so it's chain one to move over to the
next space
and then
three
treble crochets one
two and three
we'll then chain one to move over to the
next space
but this time
we've reached the peak so if you feel
like you're going to get confused
you can put a a stitch marker into this
chain two space
but we're always going to do the same in
this chain two space
and that's that little cluster of
stitches so we'll do
three trebles
one
two
and three
chain two to create that peak
and then three trebles one
two
and three
so that's
the same stitches that we do in each of
these chain two spaces as we build
we'll then chain one to move over into
that next space
and do three trebles
one
two
and three
remember the more you build the more of
these
single spaces you'll have along the way
so for example
when you get to this next row
you'll have two of these spaces before
you either reach the peak or the end of
the row
so now all we have left on this row
is this chain one space
so we're going to chain one
and then work three trebles into this
chain one space
one
two
and three
chain one and do another
treble crochet
and that's the end
of row three
so i'll just show you one more row
just to
explain the pattern repeat again but
this is basically what you're going to
do
until you get to your desired
size
or if you want to stop here you can
simply tie off
you can obviously change colors as well
here and there if you want to
so as a repeat of row three we're going
to
chain four
turn our work
and work three trebles
into that very first chain one space one
two
and three
then we're going to repeat this um
pattern until we get to
the chain two corner peak
which is
chain one
three trebles into the next space
one two
three
we have more spaces this time so chain
one
three trebles
into the next space one
two
and three
we're going to chain one to move over
into this corner chain two space
and we're going to repeat that
um
that peak pattern
so it's three trebles
one
two
and three
chain two to create the peak
and then three trebles
one
two
and three
chain one to move over to the next space
and three trebles
one
two
and three
chain one to move to the next space
and three trebles
one
two
and three
chain one to move over to the final
space which is this final chain one
where we do
three trebles one
two
and three
chain one and do a further treble
into that chain one space
so i'm going to go ahead and build a few
more rows of this now so that you can
start to see what it builds like
but this is a really simple pattern
and as i say can be used in different
ways
so keep building rewind the video if you
need to and i'll see you in a moment to
show you what this can look like once it
gets bigger
okay so here is what the triangle is
looking like as it builds
as i say you could be making
larger granny squares
you could tilt the granny squares
and have them um on this side so a
granny square could go here for example
and this fills in the corners
if you want to make a different looking
blanket or you could just keep going and
turn this into a shawl
which is just a really simple shawl to
make really nice for gifts
obviously you can change colors um
so yeah
this is the triangle granny motif
i really hope that you have enjoyed it
don't forget i'll leave all of the links
in the description box below including
the written tutorial for this
uh the blog post has all of the
information you need including the
pinnable image if you want to save it
for a later date
leave me a comment in the comment
section if you give this a go share with
your friends who you think might like
this tutorial and also don't forget to
subscribe to my channel it's absolutely
free click that bell button and you'll
be notified of when my videos go live
thank you so much for watching and i
shall see you again next time
[Music]
you